[music] All right, what's up my friends?
Welcome to the complete set review for
Reality Fracture.
White, blue, black, and red are all
done. Now we're on green going over all
the cards in the set for constructed and
limited. Give out the awards you know
and love and car bone bone. Okay, he's
very happy now. So, um, we're ready to
rock and roll. Support the content, of
course. Like, comment, subscribe,
support the comments on as always, a lot
of work goes into the show. I appreciate
your support. We got 10 new brewers
coming up. We got Bronze coming up. And
we're also brought to you by Are you
ready to elevate your limited game?
Introducing Magic the Gathering Arena
Limited Stats by Untapped GG to make
every draft count. Whether you're a
seasoned player or just starting, our
meta tier list shows you the best colors
to draft and how popular they are, so
you know at a glance what colors to
pick. Navigate card ratings to discover
the strongest bombs, or dive deeper with
our advanced view for detailed
breakdowns. Ever wonder what it takes to
get seven wins? Explore trophy decks
from other players, study winning
drafts, and replicate their [music]
successes. Victory is just a click away
at mtga.tapped.gg.
Your path to mythic starts here.
>> All right, let's do this with Arcane.
Oh, come on.
>> Somebody's playing a prank on me.
Amysia.
Amphysabania.
>> You're saying it wrong.
>> Amphysania. Anyone to metaphor a one-
one death touch whenever it enters
empower Jace 2. I think this card is an
absolute banger. So what does empower
two Jace mean? That means make a token.
A Jace planaineswalker token. The first
ever. And uh empower is kind of like a
mass where you if you don't have a
token, make a token. If you have a
token, add the number to it. So empower
Jace 2 here is two counters on the Jace.
The shortcut for this is minus three
draw minus one surveill. So it's it's
two two/ird of a Jace. It's also a
really really good blocker. I'm a huge
fan of just random death touch guys in
limited in general as far as blocking
goes. And the blue green draft archetype
in this set is called Jayce's Mastery.
quote unquote. Keep empowering Jace to
provide a steady flow of cards or make
your path to victory with cards that
grant your planes walkers abilities. So,
this is a great way to defend your Jace
and get your Jace train going, which is
kind of cool. Uh, I think this card is
excellent. Really, really good. Ain't
the bomb in common, though. Sorry, Jace.
Because our next card is the bomb in
common in Beastial Incursion.
Call the herd. Eat your heart out.
Formula for a sorcery. Make a 44 beast
of trample. Flashback for six. That is
awesome.
>> Good lord.
Gigantism.
>> 44 travel for four is not good enough,
but not far below the bar. And then bam,
you just draw a six- mana version of
that card, too. Awesome. Awesome card. I
think this card is great. Bomb and
green. Uh, excellent, excellent draft
card. And, uh, just plays really, really
well. The card's awesome. Uh, I don't
know what to say. It's just pretty
pretty solid card. So, be guard best. Uh
uh bomb and common for green unlimited
not playbook constructed. Next up is
budding insurgent. The metaphor a 33
vigilance. Sack this creature to destroy
target artifact or enchantment. If that
permanent was a legendary enchantment,
draw a card only as a sorcery. Uh
there's a saying in game design uh when
things are elegant or not elegant. Uh an
elegant card is a card that just reads
super cleanly but solves some sort of
problem or goal. um in a very very
unique and clever way. Inelegant cards
are extremely prescriptive what they do
and they're clearly targeted to do one
particular thing uh in a way that's very
very like text scripted. This is that uh
this is clearly meant to destroy the the
legendary enchantments, the way
enchantments that make uh the extra
planes walker abilities
uh in a way that is going to make you
not feel bad about disenchanting an
enchantment that already did its thing
uh by giving you a card back. Uh that's
all they're meant to do. That's a very
very very clean on non-clean clunky way
to do that which is fine. I mean this
card is fine. like three vigils for
three. Uh that can be disenchant is is
reasonable enough, but filler level
common very clunky though. Dminus on
elegance. Uh not a fan. [laughter]
Compel brutality to meta for an instant.
Choose one. Uh creatur control deals
damage equals power to creature or
planeswalker opponent controls. Or a
planaineswalker you control deals damage
equal to it loyalty to a creature or
planes walker opponent controls. So
pretty cool card. It's your typical bite
spell. uh it can bite their
planaineswalkers or make your planes
walkers bite their stuff which is kind
of cool actually. So if you're if you
have a big Jason in play, you can use
your Jace to terminate their stuff which
is kind of sweet honestly. Kind of a
cool uh mono green rule spell that
doesn't require a creature which is
pretty unique where in theory you could
play a creatureless all Planaineswalker
deck uh and have this be a green doom
blade and they usually can't kill your
planaineswalker response. So kind of a
cool card. Obviously you wouldn't do
magic strong playing real rubble spells
but this is a great version of his
trick. Um
big fan like card a lot. Really really
good really really good draft card. Uh
yeah it's great.
Greenhouse Propagator for a two three.
It's a soul warden. Whenever another
creatur you control enters you gain one
life and taps for a green. It's two
three. The green white uh vigor bloom uh
draft archetype is all about life gain
stuff. So this is a way to trigger your
Johnny's pride mates and friends over
and over and over again which is pretty
good. So mostly exciting in that
archetype although it's cool in the red
green ramp archetype too which is kind
of cool. So it's a fine draft common
nothing crazy.
Inspired tether mage the meta 4 a 32.
Have you put one or more loyalty
counters on a Planaineswalker? Put a
counter on this creature. And six mana
empower Jace 2. It's fine. Filler
common. Uh again, another one of those
glue commons which is like in between
archetypes where it's like obviously
good in the blue green Jace archetype.
It's good in the red green ramp
archetype. It's just fine otherwise. So
kind of a filler but whatever. It's
cool.
Something worth saving. Big story beat.
two for an instant milfor. Put a
permanent card of among them onto your
hand and gain one life. Same card a
million times. Uh the one life is kind
of relevant uh in your vigor bloom life
gain decks where you trigger your
giant's primate effect, whatever else it
might be. Kind of cool. Being an instant
uh is pretty cool too is it makes them
uh it makes you know kind of combat
trick but you know does what it does if
you're digging for bombs or playing life
gain stuff. It'll do that for you.
There's really a graveyard deck aside
from black uh blue, so it doesn't really
help there. Uh but yeah, it's fine.
Shoreshot sewer to mana for a 3-1 reach.
Four mana, discard a card, and plummet
something. It's fine, you know. It's
mana for a 3-1 with reach is just good
enough by itself. So passable uh
passable passable to two common. Nothing
too crazy.
Other mage advantage one mana 4 eight
instant plus two plus two reach and
untap
s card basically in every set it's a
fringe limited trigger and nothing more
vine lasher uh adept this is the land
cyclinger in green six mana for a two
four reach when it enters but three
counters on it on a creature and has
basic land cycling so base rate 5 six
reach for six which is not really that
exciting um there is some counter
synergy and of course land cycle is good
too that being said, I think this is one
of the weaker ones. Although noting that
again, black has a uh a four mana
zombify for creatures mana value six or
less and both the green and black land
cyclers are six drops. So, little extra
oomph there, but overall just kind of a
whatever common. And then wrecking
gecko, five mana for a five artifact
construct ward two six mana plus war and
trample. Uh it's okay. Okay, I mean a
five five war two for five isn't that
bad. It stabilizes reasonably well. Not
a bad mana sync. Of course, the uh con
the constari mana ramp archetype in red
green wants payoffs for mana ramp. That
being said, this is kind of a limited
filler common. Not that exciting. Moving
on to the uncommons, we get Edgar,
Moonlit Sovereign. This is a werewolf
version of the vampire. A little little
uh you know, Twilight Edward stuff going
on here. Five mana for a 44 flash.
Beginning of your end step. If you
didn't cast a spell this turn, put two
counters on Edgar. And then five mana,
put a counter on each creature you
control with a counter on it. So a
little shade of the Innistrad werewolf
stuff happening here, but not playing
spells.
I mean, sure, it's a man-ynink. It's
okay. Not a great card, which is fine.
You know, four four five is has some has
some utility in combat, which is kind of
cool. So that's fun.
Bibbleip
knows the way.
>> Inconceivable.
>> Uh, wow. Okay, he's not lost anymore.
Green green X for star two has domain
power equals the number of basic land
types among lands you control. And when
it enter search library for up to X
basic lands with different names, reveal
them and put them in your hand, then
shuffle. So, uh, even at base value,
this is like a civic wayfinder, you
know, three mana for a 22 draw land.
Sure, this can scale up pretty cool. Um,
you know, if you're splashing or being
uh, what's it called? Being a uh, you
know, a soupy deck unlimited. Say you're
playing three or four colors. Card's
kind of awesome. Uh, hits pretty hard,
finds all your colors.
It's kind of cool, honestly. Pretty
sweet. And um yeah, it's cool. Cool
card, cool draft card, nothing more.
Flourishing grapple, one mana for an
instant. Uh creature or planes walker
and opponent controls it red or white.
Loses all abilities and target creature
control deals damage equal to its power
to that permanent.
Every other color hate card uh has been
a mirror of a enemy colored version. I
don't recall what uh card this is
mirroring back to. Uh but pretty good
cyborg card. Um obviously having to
target your own stuff it is has a
inherent amount of risk that they kill
your thing in response which can be
risky. Um but yeah I mean you know it's
a fringe cyborg card and not much more
than that. It's really it.
Galta the unstoppable.
>> Good lord.
>> That's a big dinosaur. nine mana for an
88 uh cost access the cast or access the
greatest power creatures you control
which is a pretty big deal uh has
trample and gives things trample this is
a good limited card right if I have a
four four in play uh this thing costs
five and five mana for an 88 trample is
pretty insane so banger limited card
mostly it uh ga proper is actually legal
and standard right now uh so is
slumbering trudge so like you could get
this thing out pretty fast with a trudge
Um,
know that it's not like regular Galta in
that it doesn't count all the power,
just the highest power that you have.
Uh, so probably not a thing instant, but
a great limited card.
Heartwood Crafter.
This is a a pretty cool Magic the
Gathering card. Our sleeper award winner
for green. Heartwood crafter is a
prepared creature. One one for one.
Enters prepared. It taps to add a
colorless but can't be spent to cast
spells from your hand. So, this can ca
cast spells from your prepared zone in
soul tether make a heartwood token. Uh
it can cast cards from exile cards in
the graveyard. Uh activate abilities
which is pretty sweet honestly. Um Omen
Hawkeresque
and uh that's pretty cool. it if if
Badger Moub was legal, uh this would
turn it into a Lanner, which is kind of
cool. Um but yeah, this is a really
really fun buildaround card with a lot
of cool things going on. Uh you know,
worst case scenario, this is turn one
crafter to earn to play a Gr Signet,
which is kind of cool. Um and these
things do come in untap, so you can tap
it immediately and play a burst
lightning or whatever. Um yeah, this is
pretty sweet. I I don't know exactly
what you want to do with this card as is
often the case with sleeper cards, but I
think it has some pretty uh pretty heavy
utility and pretty cool possibilities.
So that's why I th sleeper card for
green. Heartwood crafter definitely look
looking into building a 10 new bre this
deck. This card
hunter's axe one green for an equipment
gets plus two plus O. It has creature
attacks. It gains trample or death touch
and equips for two.
I mean, there's been worse bone
spplitters, I guess. I think it's
probably just worse than bone splitter
straight up, but if you're looking for a
way to push through in your draft, like
I guess this does that. There isn't
really any synergy for equipment or for
artifacts. So, you're kind of just, you
know, what you see is what you get,
which probably isn't good enough despite
the really cool art. Uh, but yeah, range
limited card, nothing more.
Damn. Uh,
Yang Yan Yangu, never alone. Formula 4,
a 22. Uh, when Yang Yu enters, make a
Mau, a legendary 33 dog token. Endstep,
untap all tokens you control. I mean,
fine. Limited card. Just format three, a
three and a T2 is pretty good. A little
bit of value in the untapping. It's
fine. Kind of a filler limited card.
loot the nexus, who somehow manages to
look just as horrifying as the mono
black loot.
Ah,
the meta for a 2-1 taps for a color and
adds one mana of that color for each
different power among creatures you
control.
Pretty high ceiling card. Not hard to
have a tap for two, three, or even four
mana. It counts itself, of course. So,
say I just have this in play and a one-
one task for two, which is great. And uh
I can go a lot higher than that as well.
Pretty powerful card. Uh you do get to
add any color. So, it's it's a fixture
for your soup deck.
Yeah, I mean card's pretty cool. Cool.
Cool draft card. Again, red green is a
ramp archetype. So, this card is kind of
sweet. Little fragile. Not good enough
for constructed, but I think it is a
pretty cool limited card.
Marwin the preserver to mana for a 32
lands have hex proof which I guess is a
thing that can happen um sure more
importantly it has two mana return a
land card your graveyard to your hand uh
that can be fetchlands for example it's
an elf and there is the uh the hobbit
elf fetchland from the hobbit uh or
whatever other land effects there might
be guard's fine uh it plays well the
bobing wilds kind of things or land
cyclers or rumaging etc., etc. It's
fine. Just a fine card. Fine stat lines
and card advantage. Not much else. You
know, the problem is like when you make
every creature a legend, a lot of them
are like this where it just doesn't feel
like a legend. Just feels like some
random uncommon. But it's fine.
Pia aether aesthetic. So, we have the
monogreen Pia. The metaphor A22. When it
enters, you may discard a card. If you
do search your library for an
enchantment card, reveal it, put it in
your hand, and then shuffle. This is the
kind of card where it's pretty bad and
limited. I don't think it really has a
place in standard, but could be really
good in older formats or in commander,
etc., etc., uh, where
this is just I don't think we've ever
had a cheap way to tutor up enchantments
in green before. Uh, discard literally
any card and put the enchantment into
your hand. It's pretty powerful.
card's pretty good honestly. You know,
not quite formidable speaker, but
finding an enchantment is very very very
very unique. So, kind of a cool tutor
effect. I imagine we'll see play in
various spots in in various places. Uh
yeah, it's cool. Small, not very high on
on pure rate, but pretty cool effect.
This could find Alluren or whatever and
so on and so forth. So, it's cool.
Restore with empathy. They're met up for
an instant return a permanent card of
vigor to your hand and gain four life.
[snorts]
It's fine again for uh vigor bloom
gaining four life in the middle of
combat. It's a pretty cool place to be
for like synergy and tricks. Uh four
life is a pretty good buffer for making
up for the fact that you're paying a
three mana extra tax on whatever spell
you're getting back. Um if you have
bombs, cool. It's fine. It's a cool
card. Um,
yeah, fine. Fine. Limited card. Not much
more. Rurickthar, Mage Crusher, seven
mana, 7 seven, can't be countered.
Reach, vigilance, trample, and has
hexroof as long as it hasn't dealt
combat damage yet.
Um, yeah, I mean, pretty good limited
card. It's big enough where it's kind of
nice and they can't really uh attack
into it until it deals damage. So, solid
limited card. Seven's a lot, but it is
of course uh you know the ramp
archetypes of red green can cast this
card and so on and so forth. It's fine.
Kind of just like your you know I need a
big bopper and limited. Here it is. And
uh let's just do it.
Just the big fun guy. Tiny bones.
>> Good lord.
Gigantism.
>> What do they do to tiny bones? [music]
>> Tiny bones. Like
You had one job.
>> I guess he I'm sorry I'm saying tiny
bones. It is actually Titan bones. I
apologize. So Titan Bones Towering
Heart. Don't know how this works, but
for mana for a 43 reach. Whenever you
gain life, put two counters on Titan
Bones. If you ever discard this card,
you gain three life. So clearly a card
made for the uh the green white life
gain archetype. It's like a super
Johnny's Pride mate, which is pretty
good. You know, there's a number of ways
to gain life for free. So, um, yeah, I
mean, pretty good limited card, not
great otherwise, you know, uh, the
discard effect is not really worth a
card. You know, it's not an opposite of
bailout or whatever where like you'd
board this in against discard effects.
So, it's fine. Limited card
way of the paradox. So, again, we have
two of these in each color pair of the
enchantments that uh, empower Jace and
then give extra abilities or other
effects. This is three mana for empower
Jace five. Whenever you activate a
loyalty ability, you gain one life and
you may play an extra land this turn. So
base level, this is three mana explore
put a Jace two in play, which is pretty
good. And then the life gain is
relevant, too. There uh the Ajani or one
of the white ways of you gain life, you
add loyalty to Planaineswalkers. So
there's definitely some some mixing
parts here. uh doing some cool stuff.
And uh yeah, I mean guard's pretty cool.
Uh I think his guard's subtly pretty
powerful. Again, there's a lot of moving
parts with these way enchantments where
it's really hard to kind of piece
together the pieces of what it's going
to look like before playing with it. But
this guard's pretty cool. Uh I'm a fan
card
and it does stack. So yes, in theory,
say you had four planes walkers in play
and they all drew cards. You could like
playwalker plus draw card, play a land,
playwalker plus draw, play a land, play
walker plus draw, play a land, etc. So
pretty cool. The other way is way of the
wild speaker, which is five mana,
empower J7, which is a lot. And it gives
all planes walkers you control the
ability minus four loyalty, make a 44.
Pretty good. Again, base value in
limited. This is a five mana 44.
uh that leaves behind a JSON three draw
card, which is pretty good. But as long
as you're empowering more, it's really
powerful. Again, the blue green
archetype is all about empowering Jace a
lot. So yeah, this card's pretty cool.
Probably not good enough for
constructed, but pretty fun. Limited
card. I really love this Jace token
limited. I think it's so cool. So I like
it a lot.
Yoshiaru Scrappy Stray, they're
monsters.
Karna, don't look wherever you are. Not
working.
Yoshimaru is falling on tough times. Uh,
little mangy here. Two mana for a 1-1.
Uh, whatever Yoshimaru enters another
creature you control, fights up to one
dark creature your opponent controls and
then six mana to put a counter on target
non-leendary creature. Uh, so it's kind
of the opposite of the of the white one.
That being said, I mean, two mana for a
one- one with some text on it that also
can be a fight effect is fine. Not
great. Fights aren't nearly as good as
bites these days. Um, but yeah, this is
a file little card. Um,
yeah, sure. Chad says Jace deserved it.
Wow.
Wow. Onto the rares. Carnivorous
Cultivator. It's a trap
>> is our trap card. Uh, I like this card a
lot. It's really cool, but I just don't
think it's as good as it looks. to man
up for a two three death touch enters
prepared real combat damage to a player
and may return a land card from your
graveyard to your hand. Okay, the
prepared spell is in route which is just
in for a land uh for a land card put in
the graveyard then shuffle. So obviously
you can play this and then you can in
route into a land attack get it back in
theory
is is
okay
and
like sure it's a lot of hoops to just
you know silven scrying a land on this
creature that has to hit and yada yada
yada and I think the creature itself is
just kind of fine you So, if you're just
doing like a fetch land attack and back
fetch land yada yada yada. Um, that's
like okay, but is okay good? Not really.
So, yeah, I don't know. It's an elf and
there is an elf fetch land standard uh
from the Hobbit, which is a thing. You
know, not the easiest to block, but I
just struggle to envision like what deck
really cares that much about this. Um,
if strip min was legal, sure, fine. Why
not? Uh, but it's not.
>> Give me what I want.
>> I'm just kidding. I don't want that. Uh,
but yeah, I don't know. Great and
limited cuz a two three death touch for
two is just a fine limited card. But for
constructed, I'm not a fan. I think this
card looks cool and just is not going to
play very well at all. Carniviverse
cultivator is your trap card for green
garden. The art in this is horrifying.
horrifying. Uh the mana enchantment
never you control dies put a charge
counter as enchantment being your first
main phase add a green for each charge
counter on this enchantment. I feel like
if this card was green black one, it
would be pretty good. But having double
green in the cost where you really play
as a black in theory is uh
get out of here, man.
It's just kind of rough, you know. Um it
is kind of Sorry, that wasn't really
loud. Uh it is kind of cute with uh
spawn tokens and like modern and stuff
like who cares really. Um, I think this
card is just it has some pretty decent
potential, but like you got to play it.
You got to have creatures in play. They
need to have things to do with all the
mana.
I think it's whatever. And then limited
cards totally unplayable. Don't put this
card in your deck.
Hungering puppet beast five mana for a
five. When it enters, make a heartwood
token uh which is a red green token.
It's a mana rock taster red or green and
uh one mana sacrifice another artifact.
put a counter this creature gains a
trample hex proof or haste until end of
turn.
It's a great limited card. You know, a
five five for five that uh ramps you,
makes an artifact, and then has haste
and hexroof occasionally. It's pretty
cool. You can use the token you make to
activate the ability because it comes in
untap, which is cool. So, you can play
it heartwood go of hexroof or whatever
else. Uh effectively, it can have haste.
It's like a five mana haste for fives.
It's charging monster store, which is
pretty cool. So, it's a great card for
limited uh on just like on your on rate,
but I struggle to imagine a red green or
a a green ne would want constructed.
It's just like not good enough. So,
I don't know. It's fine. It's okay.
Great limited, but
puppet crafting. It's metaphor a
enchantment aura enchanting artifact or
nonora enchantment. Chain of Permanent
is a construct that's a base power five5
and that's five mana. Return this card
from your graveyard to your hand.
Uh I mean it's interesting like turning
a random clue or treasure into a five is
not too shabby. Like imagine turn one
the Inspector turn two this and the
clue. That's not too bad. Come on, man.
Um, sorry. Uh, yeah. I mean, it's kind
of a cool card. It's, you similar to a
soul artifact in some ways, though being
green is kind of weird. Um, green can
make food pretty easily, too.
This card might be a sleeper, honestly.
Um,
and of course, it could come back as the
game goes on.
Yeah, this card's cute. Honestly, I
card's better than it looks. I guess a
sleeper card in uh con in limited
con can constari makes them out of
rocks. You can use it to t to animate
those. That's really it though in
limited uh but it constructed I mean the
card's pretty cool. Yeah. I mean has
pretty good you know pedigree compared
to a uh to the install artifact. So yeah
I mean cool green monogreen and soul
artifact. Who would have thought you'd
see bedet you know?
Oh man.
>> A
fs in chat for uh solemn simulacrim.
>> Who?
>> You know who solemn singer lacrim is.
Keep my solemn's name out your damn
mouth. All right.
>> Language.
>> Similacrim. Shaper. Three mana for a
two2. So similacrim ed search for a
land. When it dies, draw a card. FS in
chat for the sab robot. Um so is in
standard right now. It's not very good.
uh at three mana. I'm not even sure if
Solom's good at three mana, honestly.
It's also green green, which is kind of
tough. Uh you know, I think if was a an
artifact, it would be great. Uh but
I don't know what heavy green deck wants
to play this. It being an elf is kind of
cute, you know, for some elf synergy or
whatever else it might be. Uh but yeah,
card's sweet. I mean, it's a great
limited card. Like excellent
constructed. I wouldn't count them out.
I'm just not sure what like deck would
want to play this. Uh, you know, it's
it's fighting against Earth Bender,
Ascension, all these other ramp cards,
you know, and like I don't think
Standard really has a place uh for this
random, you know, kind of slight value
small creature.
It's just not if if standard was more
like, you know, standard
six to eight sets, etc., etc., this card
would be great, but as standard is it's
more like Pioneer Modern, which is so
fast. I think this card is going to be
fall by the wayside. So, cool card. Uh,
but yeah, great limited card, but for
constructor, probably not. Verdant
Kraken, seven mana for a 66 B players
upkeep. Make a 66 green forest tentacle
land token. Uh, I mean, windmill slam
bomb unlimited. Uh, just 66 go 33 untap
33. If you hit that point, you probably
can't lose. For constructivist is kind
of cool for landfall. Uh you are making
land tokens. So this is a way to play
this and say go landfall on their turn,
etc., etc. Um I don't think that's good
enough for the landfall decks, but I do
think this card is pretty sweet. Uh and
it's ridiculous and limited, so it's
cool. Time to get cracking.
And again, Constar is a ramp deck, so
pretty sweet.
Garrick, Curse Breaker, five mana mythic
Garrick and uh it's pretty good. Has a
static creature uh power four greater
enters draw a card. No cap on that. You
should keep doing it. Plus two untap two
lands minus to make a 44 minus four till
your next turn. Whenever one or more
creatures attack one of your opponents,
they get plus two and trample to end a
turn.
If it was 2018, this would have been
bested show. Uh, it's not.
This card is ridiculous. Uh, really,
really powerful. The floor of this card
is kind of like five mana for a 44 that
draws a card on ETB and makes two
loyalty planes walk ETB, which is very
good. Uh, but again, standard is just
not really like that these days, you
know. Uh, so,
you know, it's really powerful. Uh,
overrun's pretty cool, too. But I just
don't know if this card can really make
it in standard these days, which is kind
of a sad thing. This card looks really
cool, but it's a unbeatable bomb
unlimited. But yeah, you know, I think
this card is probably fringe player at
best in standard. I hope I'm wrong. It's
pretty sweet. Uh, untapping two ends is
quite potent, but uh, we shall see. I
think that like, you know, play Garrick
plus two hold up a a counter spell
removal spell is pretty cool. It's not
not a bad pattern. But is this card by
the Delenfell?
I don't know. I don't think so, you
know. So, is it is really fun card
though.
Hex Haven Invigorator. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I'll give the best and show to Hack Save
invigorator. Uh green, green, green,
green for a Chimera horror. 66
vigilance. Never dealt damage. Search
library for up to that many land cards.
Put the battlefield tap then shuffle.
This is the fraian obliterator, you
know, mirrored version. even though we
already have like the white one too. Uh
card is pretty busted. It's I think this
card is
honestly not as good in standard as
perhaps other formats. It searches for
any lands not basics. So for example, I
saw a deck list recently uh for modern
playing invigorator and mine collapse
which is a sack of mountain deal five
something and you just kill your
opponent with bal spot uh which is kind
of cute. So has applications there.
Obviously fight spells, same thing.
Plays on turn five with a fight spell.
Pretty insane. The thing is in in
standard,
what lands are you getting? You what are
you so excited to get with this thing
that's like really really, you know,
really really getting you going. Uh but
it's still a really powerful effect. I
think this card is a little overrated,
but I do think it's very very powerful.
Uh you know, every once in a while I'll
not be contrarian and just take the
really powerful card. You know, bossing
say is cool with some creature lands.
There are a lot of lands in the format.
you know, field of ruin, so on and so
forth. Um, but yeah, cool fight spells.
Uh, you get the idea. In limit, if you
can cast this card, it's un it's just
typical for ex where it's unbeatable.
They they can't kill it. But if they're
playing white or black or rubble, they
just can. So, you know, is what it is.
And there is a green valet variant uh in
the lands. More on that in a bit. But
yeah, best in show hex inig invigorator.
I can't wait to cast unlimited. That
sounds really fun.
Omniresence, not omniscience,
omniresence. Uh, that's some uh some
spaghetti monsters here. Six mana,
sorry, eight mana for a enchantment. You
may cast spells mana value less than or
equal to the number of land creatures
you control from your hand without
paying their mana cost. So, a pretty
high ceiling card uh where I have a
bunch of elves in play. I cast this on
turn four and then just cast my entire
hand, yada yada yada. That's pretty uh
risky. And then you need to actually
have things to play too. So I think this
card's pretty bad. Um you basically have
to cast this card to be excited about it
because you're putting it in off Kona or
cheating it in. Just play omnitions
while you play this card. So I think
this card is uh yeah a little win more
for sure. Um,
yeah. You know, it's uh it's a card.
>> Pointless nostalgia.
>> I'm in danger.
>> No warts. No trap card here. Tariff is
back and uh a real uh testament to power
creep in the 2020s is them bringing back
all of these old cards that were just so
good back in the day that are now just
also rans. You could play Dark Confidant
and to in standard in 2026 and I don't
think either one's even close to good
enough. Uh, I do think this card is
probably playableish.
You definitely would want to be playing
uh like not just playing it straight up.
Like back in the day, you played Sargo.
It's funny. So, when little history of
this card, when this card first came
out, it was uh future site. Uh, I was
playing competitively and on the pro
tour and stuff and the first event it
was legal was Grand Prix I believe
Montreal which was time spiral block
constructed. Okay. and me Jay played in
it and I built this like green white
like tarmaggoy mystic enforcer like deck
that was playing like chromatic star
edge of edge of autumn to cycle your
flag stones just like trying really hard
to get a lot of different types in the
graveyard aggressively and like really
used armag to its maximum ability this
is also to was like a $3 card uh we
found out that you didn't really need to
do that you could just play the card
normally because a four five for two was
like busted back then uh but you know I
was trying to do it the full way back
then. I think now in standard if Tom
McGwave was going to be playable you
will need to do that kind of stuff
because a two out of four five is not
good enough anymore. So, playing
artifacts, enchantments, planes,
walkers, yada yada yada or just having
different types available, you know,
what does it need to be? Not really
sure. Uh, but it's funny because last 10
new Bruce
say 10 new Bruce is coming out. Last 10
new Bruce, we built a boomer Jun deck
almost as like a joke with like Dark
Confidant, you know, Dark Confidant, the
blood the Blood Raid off proxy, you
know, like, oh, we're building Jund. How
funny is this? And now we can just do it
with actual tarag too which is you know
I don't know um tar is still good. I
don't think this is a trap card. I think
this card has you know a chance to see
some fringe play. It's still very good
limited you know uh but yeah there is
some and honestly red green delirium is
a deck in standard that wants to play
the card breakout uh which is good with
too. So, I think his guard is not as
it's it would be easy bait to save us as
a trap card, but I think his guard has
some legs and we'll see some play before
it's all over. So, there you go on
Taragif.
So, to recap for green, hex haven
invigorator best in best show.
Horcrafter is your sleeper card. Carniv
carnivorous cultivator is your trap card
and beastial incursion is your bomb and
common. Multicolor is coming up next,
folks. And Multicolor is packed. All
right, so support the content, like,
comment, subscribe, and I'll see you in
multicolor.
Let's go.